A Guide to the Elizabeth Oakes Smith Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8326-c
Elizabeth Oakes Smith Collection 1843-1883
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8326-c
10 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1968 May 21 ] 1968 Sep 26
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Poem, " Unattained ", 1881 Sep 2; AMsS, 3 p.
    [Includes note to [O. S.] Baldwin at the end; thanks him for papers he sent to her and for keeping up the interest of the "Monthly."]
  - Poem, " With the Skin of a Monkey ", 1881 Jan 1; AMsS, 2 p.
    [Inscribed to Corinne Baldwin. ]
- Letters
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1875 Sep 14; ALS, 3 p.
    [Relates some gossip in regard to "Stonewall" Jackson's wife [ Anna Morrison Jackson]; says that, according to family gossip, Harriet Beecher proposed to Dr. Storrs after his first wife died; says that Dr. Storrs' first wife was related to Smith and was a daughter of theologian Bennett Tyler; promises to send Baldwin autographs of her friends.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1875 Oct 5; ALS, 3 p.
    [Reports on her election to "Worthy Chief Templar" of the Grand Lodge of the State of North Carolina; says she was also elected delegate to the Grand Worthy International Lodge; sends him a few autographs upon request; says she is disappointed not to find her contribution in the October issue of
    Baldwin's Monthly
    . ]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1876 Jan 20; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sends him an autograph of Mrs. Eames; gives an account of her life: Mrs. Eames' father forced her to break off her engagement to Horace Greeley; says Eames wrote some poetry which interested Edgar Allan Poe; thinks of Eames as interesting in a weird way.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1876 Mar 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for a box of interesting papers, including
    , Art Journal, etc.; says she has sent him the autograph of Anne Charlotte Lynch Botta who sold her valuable collection of autographs to Russell Sage of Brooklyn; says Botta established a prize with the obtained money to be awarded for the best work on the "Condition of Women," to be written in French, and to be awarded every 5 years by the French Academy.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to unknown, 1876 May 15; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sends autograph of Thomas Cole; speaks of her admiration for the painter; says his pictures "The Voyage of Life" prompted her to write four sonnets.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1877 Oct 5; ALS, 3 p.
    [Describes her duties as pastor of the Independent Church of Canostota, New York; describes the church community; encourages him to send a parcel of
    to be passed around; says it would be a good advertisement for him; sends an article of hers which he might like to publish.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1877 Dec 28; ALS, 2 p.
    [Acknowledges his Christmas gift; comments on the January edition to the Journal; requests another copy of a little "note" of hers he will publish.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to [O. S.] Baldwin, 1881 Sep 28; ALS, 3 p.
    [Comments on the depressing times the country is experiencing due to the death of the president, failing crops, etc.; remarks on "Mother Shippen's" prophecies; acknowledges receipt of $3 for poem entitled "
    Unattained
    "; says she is presently writing an article on the latitude claimed by American women.]